Gerrit Smith Papers
Gerrit Smith Papers
- Miscellaneous
  - Peterboro Children's Home, 1871-1887; holograph and clippings (Box 153)
  - Peterboro Temperance Meeting Resolution, 1835; holoqraph, 2 leaves (Box 153)
  - Petition for Repeal of the Fugitive Slave Law, 1851; printed with holograph signatures, 1 leaf (Box 153)
  - Practical Democrats, "Address of the Practical Democrats", 1854; printed material, 7 pp.; also clipping with "Platform of the Practical Democrats," 1 p.; 2 copies (Box 153)
  - Portraits of Gerrit Smith, undated; 2 different reproductions (Box 153)
  - Printed matter on abolition, temperance, state support of churches, etc., 1847-1863 (Box 153)
  - Reciprocal trade agreement with Canada
    - Correspondence re, 1853; holograph (Box 153)
    - Printed material related to, 1849-1853 (Box 153)
  - Scrapbooks of clippings, broadsides and genealogical records
    - [scrapbook A] (vol.100), 1834-1904 (Box 154)
    - [scrapbook B] (vol.101), 1834-1873 (Box 154)
  - Shipman Pension Case, 1852-1853; correspondence and printed material (Box 154)
  - Sermon Book, Johann Kaspar Lavater, 1762; holograph, 28pp., in German (Box 154)
  - New York State Lunatic Asylum, Utica, New York, 1859-1860; correspondence, itemized lists and clippings (Box 154)
  - Gerrit Smith vs. the New York Democratic Vigilant Association, 1860; undated; re John Brown's Raid on Harper's Ferry (Box 154)
  - Correspondence, Mar-Nov 1860; undated; 2 folders (Box 154)
  - Miscellaneous, 1859-1860; includes holograph notes, clippings, "Address of the Vigilant Association of the City of New York", printed 27pp. and three copies of "Gerrit Smith and the Vigilant Association of the City of New York", John A. Gray, printer, 27pp (Box 154)
  - Zecher, George William, Case, 1854-1869; correspondence (most in German), holograph; 2 folders (Box 154)
  - Lovejoy, Owen, "State of the Union", 23 Jan 1861; printed material, 8pp. (Box 155)
  - Marks, E. Letter to Dear Cousin W.B., Camillus, Onondaga Co., NY, 12 Feb 1862; printed material (Box 155)
  - Nuermberger, Ruth Ketríng, The Free Produce Movement: A Quaker Against Slavery, Durham, North Carolina, Duke University Press (Historical Papers of the Trinity College Historical Society, Series XXV), 1942 (Box 155)
  - Ray, Frederick A., "Gerrit Smith, the friend of John Brown," Herkimer County Historical Society Papers, vol.4, printed, 1914 (Box 155)
  - Sperry, Earl E., The Jerry Rescue, October 5, 1851, Syracuse NY, Onondaga Historical Association, 1924 (Box 155)
  - Tanner, Edwin Platt, "Gerrit Smith: an interpretation", a paper read at the New York Historical Association, 2-4 Oct 1923; printed material, 19pp (Box 155)
  - American Anti-Slavery Almanac, NY: S.W. Benedict, 1840; 1842 (Box 155)
  - Women's Rights Almanac, Worcester, MA: 2. Baker and Co., 1858 (Box 155)
  - Blackwell, Henry B. "What the South Can Do: How the Southern States Can Make Themselves Masters of the Situation", 15 Jan 1867; printed material, 4pp (Box 155)
  - Douglass, Frederick, "Address by Frederick Douglass, and poem by A.C. Hills, delivered at the erection of the Wing Monument at Mexico, Oswego, NY, Sept 11, 1855," Syracuse: J.G.K. Truair, printer (Box 155)
  - Faithful, Emily, Three Visits to America, Edinburgh, 1884; reproduction, 2pp (Box 155)
  - Frothingham, Octavius B., Gerrit Smith: A biography 3rd ed., NT: G.P. Putnam's Sons, 1909; undated; includes photocopy of note by Greene Smith from the Greene Smith Papers, 2pp. (Box 155)
  - Hammond, Charles A. Gerrit Smith: The story of a noble man's life, Geneva, NY: W.F. Humphrey, 1900 (Box 155)
  - Harlow, Ralph V. Gerrit Smith and the John Brown Raid, reprinted from the American Historical Review, v.XXXVIII, no. 1, Oct 1932 (Box 155)
  - Harlow, Ralph V. Gerrit Smith and the Free Church Movement, reprinted from The New York History, vol.XVIII, no.3, Jul 1837 (Box 155)
  - Harlow, Ralph V. Gerrit Smith: Philanthropist and Reformer, NY: Henry Holt and Co., vol.97, 1939 (Box 155)
  - "First Through," Auburn and Ithaca Railroad, Genoa, NY, oversized illustration, removed from frame (Box map-case)
- Maps
  Maps are listed in a separate cartobibliography. (WARNING: This file is quite large and may take some time to download/open.)